<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="DFARS_204.7503" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title " rev="Revised November 10, 2025"> 
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">204.7503</ph> Procedures.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a) <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised November 10, 2025">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">CMMC level</i>.</ph> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised November 10, 2025">The contracting officer shall include the CMMC level (see 32 CFR 170.19) required by the program office or requiring activity in the solicitation provision and contract clause prescribed at 204.7504.</ph> 
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p "
            outputclass="List1"
            rev="Revised November 10, 2025"> (b) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Award</i>. Contracting officers shall check SPRS and not award a contract, task order, or delivery order to an offeror that does not have a current CMMC status posted in SPRS at the CMMC level (see 32 CFR 170.15 through 170.18) required by the solicitation, or higher, for each CMMC UID provided by the offeror. The CMMC UIDs are applicable to each of the contractor information systems that will process, store, or transmit FCI or CUI and that will be used in performance of the contract.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p "
            outputclass="List1"
            rev="Revised November 10, 2025"> (c) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Option exercise or period of performance extension</i>. Contracting officers shall check SPRS and not exercise an option or extend the period of performance on a contract, task order, or delivery order, unless the contractor has a current CMMC status posted in SPRS at the CMMC level (see 32 CFR 170.15 through 170.18) required by the contract, task order, or delivery order, or higher, for each CMMC UID provided by the contractor. The contractor’s CMMC UIDs are applicable to each of the contractor information systems that process, store, or transmit FCI or CUI and that are or will be used in performance of the contract.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p "
            outputclass="List1"
            rev="Revised November 10, 2025"> (d) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">CMMC UIDs</i>. If the contractor provides new CMMC UIDs during performance of the contract, task order, or delivery order, the contracting officer shall check in SPRS, using the CMMC UIDs assigned by SPRS, that the contractor has a current CMMC status at the required CMMC level, or higher, for each of the contractor information systems identified that will process, store, or transmit FCI or CUI during contract performance.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
