<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_204.470-2"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">204.470-2</ph> National security exclusion.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  The U.S.-IAEA AP permits the United States unilaterally to declare exclusions from inspection requirements for activities, or locations or information associated with such activities, with direct national security significance.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  In order to ensure that all relevant activities are reviewed for direct national security significance, both current and former activities, and associated locations or information, are to be considered for applicability for a national security exclusion.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  If a DoD program manager receives notification from a contractor that the contractor is required to report any of its activities in accordance with the U.S.-IAEA AP, the program manager will—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Conduct a security assessment to determine if, and by what means, access may be granted to the IAEA; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Provide written justification to the component or agency treaty office for application of the national security exclusion at that location to exclude access by the IAEA, in accordance with DoD Instruction 2060.03, Application of the National Security Exclusion to the Agreements Between the United States of America and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards in the United States of America.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
