<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-204.1103"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">204.1103</ph> Procedures.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">See PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_204.1103"
                  href="PGI_204.1103.dita#DFARS-PGI_PGI_204.1103">204.1103</xref>
             for helpful information on navigation and data entry in the System for Award Management (SAM) database.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  On contract award documents, use the contractor’s legal or “doing business as” name and physical address information as recorded in the SAM database at the time of award.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  When making a determination to exercise an option, or at any other time before issuing a modification other than a unilateral modification making an administrative change, ensure that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  The contractor’s record is active in the SAM database; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  The contractor’s Data Universal Numbering System (DUNS) number, Commercial and Government Entity (CAGE) code, name, and physical address are accurately reflected in the contract document.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  At any time, if the DUNS number, CAGE code, contractor name, or physical address on a contract no longer matches the information on the contractor’s record in the SAM database, the contracting officer shall process a novation or change-of-name agreement, or an address change, as appropriate.  </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4)  See PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_204.1103"
                  href="PGI_204.1103.dita#DFARS-PGI_PGI_204.1103">204.1103</xref>
             for additional requirements relating to use of information in the SAM database.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(5)  On contractual documents transmitted to the payment office, provide the CAGE code, instead of the DUNS number or DUNS+4 number, in accordance with agency procedures.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
