<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_209.270-2" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">209.270-2</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p>As used in this section—</p>
         <p>“Aviation critical safety item” means a part, an assembly, installation equipment, launch equipment, recovery equipment, or support equipment for an aircraft or aviation weapon system if the part, assembly, or equipment contains a characteristic any failure, malfunction, or absence of which could cause—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  A catastrophic or critical failure resulting in the loss of or serious damage to the aircraft or weapon system;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  An unacceptable risk of personal injury or loss of life; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3)  An uncommanded engine shutdown that jeopardizes safety.</p>
         <p>“Design control activity”—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  With respect to an aviation critical safety item, means the systems command of a military department that is specifically responsible for ensuring the air worthiness of an aviation system or equipment in which an aviation critical safety item is to be used; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  With respect to a ship critical safety item, means the systems command of a military department that is specifically responsible for ensuring the seaworthiness of a ship or ship equipment in which a ship critical safety item is to be used.</p>
         <p>“Ship critical safety item” means any ship part, assembly, or support equipment containing a characteristic the failure, malfunction, or absence of which could cause—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  A catastrophic or critical failure resulting in loss of or serious damage to the ship; or </p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  An unacceptable risk of personal injury or loss of life.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
