<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-209.470-2"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">209.470-2</ph> Policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, 10 U.S.C. 983 prohibits DoD from providing funds by contract or grant to an institution of higher education if the Secretary of Defense determines that the institution has a policy or practice that prohibits or in effect prevents—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The Secretary of a military department from maintaining, establishing, or operating a unit of the Senior Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) at that institution;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  A student at that institution from enrolling in a unit of the Senior ROTC at another institution of higher education;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  The Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Transportation from gaining entry to campuses, or access to students on campuses, for purposes of military recruiting; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4)  Military recruiters from accessing certain information pertaining to students enrolled at that institution.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  The prohibition in paragraph (a) of this subsection does not apply to an institution of higher education if the Secretary of Defense determines that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The institution has ceased the policy or practice described in paragraph (a) of this subsection; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  The institution has a long-standing policy of pacifism based on historical religious affiliation.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
