<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="DFARS_215.305"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            rev="Revised November 15, 2024">
      <title class="- topic/title " rev="Revised November 15, 2024">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">215.305</ph>  Proposal evaluation.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)(2) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Past performance evaluation.</i> (A) When a past performance evaluation is required by <xref href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/15.304"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">FAR 15.304</xref>, and the solicitation includes the clause at <xref href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/52.219-9"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">FAR 52.219-9</xref>, Utilization of Small Business Concerns, the evaluation factors shall include the past performance of offerors in complying with requirements of that clause. When a past performance evaluation is required by <xref href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/15.304"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">FAR 15.304</xref>, and the solicitation includes the clause at <xref href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/52.219-9"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">FAR 52.219-9</xref>, Small Business Subcontracting Plan, the evaluation factors shall include the past performance of offerors in complying with requirements of that clause. </p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B) Contracting officers shall consider an offeror's failure to make a good faith effort to comply with its comprehensive subcontracting plan under the Test Program described at <xref href="219.702-70.dita#DFARS_219.702-70"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">219.702-70</xref> as part of the evaluation of the past performance.</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(C) When evaluating the past performance of an offeror that is a small business concern in response to a competitive solicitation, contracting officers shall consider relevant past performance information provided for affiliates of the offeror.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
