<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="DFARS_216.505">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">216.505</ph> Ordering.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p id="sFNgaU" outputclass="List1">(a) <i>General.</i>
         </p>
         <p id="AMQLkJ" outputclass="List2">(6) Orders placed under indefinite-delivery contracts may be issued on DD Form 1155, Order for Supplies or Services.</p>
         <p id="fbFEGY" outputclass="List2">(S-70) Departments and agencies shall comply with the review, approval, and reporting requirements established in accordance with subpart 217.7 when placing orders under non-DoD contracts in amounts exceeding the simplified acquisition threshold.</p>
         <p id="guqYZT" outputclass="List1">(b) <i>Orders under multiple-award contracts.</i>
         </p>
         <p id="GcHyIc" outputclass="List2">(1) <i>Fair opportunity.</i>
         </p>
         <p id="BRIAHP" outputclass="List4">(A) See <xref base="DFARS-215.101-2" href="215.101-2.dita#DFARS_215.101-2" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" xtrc="215.101-2">215.101-2</xref>-70 for the limitations and prohibitions on the use of the lowest price technically acceptable source selection process, which are applicable to orders placed against multiple award indefinite delivery contracts.</p>
         <p id="uGWfmt" outputclass="List4">(B) See <xref base="DFARS-217.7801" href="217.7801.dita#DFARS_217.7801" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" xtrc="217.7801">217.7801</xref> for the prohibition on the use of reverse auctions for personal protective equipment and aviation critical safety items.</p>
         <p id="RNWBHZ" outputclass="List2">(2) <i>Exceptions to the fair opportunity process.</i> For an order exceeding the simplified acquisition threshold, that is a follow-on to an order previously issued for the same supply or service based on a justification for an exception to fair opportunity citing the authority at FAR <xref format="html" href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/part-16#FAR_16_505" scope="external">16.505</xref>(b)(2)(i)(B) or (C), follow the procedures at <xref href="PGI_216.505.dita#DFARS_PGI_PGI_216.505" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" xtrc="216.505">PGI 216.505</xref>(b)(2).</p>
         <p id="ExqGWD" outputclass="List2">(6) Postaward notices and debriefing of awardees for orders exceeding $6 million. In addition to the notice required at FAR <xref format="html" href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/part-16#FAR_16_505" scope="external">16.505</xref>(b)(6), a written or oral postaward debriefing of successful and unsuccessful awardees is required for task orders and delivery orders valued at $10 million or more (section 818 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (Pub. L. 115-91)).</p>
         <p id="qCrFXO" outputclass="List3">(ii) Follow the procedures at <xref href="216.506.dita#DFARS_216.506" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" xtrc="216.506">216.506</xref> and <xref href="215.506-70.dita#DFARS_215.506-70" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" xtrc="216.506-70">215.506-70</xref> when providing the postaward debriefing to successful and unsuccessful awardees for task orders or delivery orders valued at $10 million or more.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
