<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_217.7102" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">217.7102</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Activities shall enter into master agreements for repair and alteration of vessels with all prospective contractors located within the United States or its outlying areas, which—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Request ship repair work; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Possess the organization and facilities to perform the work satisfactorily.  (Issuance of a master agreement does not indicate approval of the contractor's facility for any particular acquisition and is not an affirmative determination of responsibility under FAR Subpart 9.1 for any particular acquisition.)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  Activities may use master agreements in work with prospective contractors located outside the United States and its outlying areas.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  Activities may issue job orders under master agreements to effect repairs, alterations, and/or additions to vessels belonging to foreign governments.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Contractors shall treat vessels of a foreign government as if they were vessels of the U.S. Government whenever requested to do so by the contracting officer.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Identify the vessel and the foreign government in the solicitation and job order.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
