<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_217.103" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">217.103</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Advance procurement” means an exception to the full funding policy that allows acquisition of long lead time items (advance long lead acquisition) or economic order quantities (EOQ) of items (advance EOQ acquisition) in a fiscal year in advance of that in which the related end item is to be acquired. Advance procurements may include materials, parts, components, and effort that must be funded in advance to maintain a planned production schedule.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Congressional defense committees,” means—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) The Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3) The Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4) The Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(5) The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(6) The Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Military installation” means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, or other activity under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department or, in the case of an activity in a foreign country, under the operational control of the Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Defense (10 U.S.C. 2801(c)(4)).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
