<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_217.7404" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">217.7404</ph> Limitations.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p>See PGI 217.7404 for additional guidance on obtaining approval to authorize use of an undefinitized contact action, documentation requirements, and other limitations on their use.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a)  <i>Foreign military sales contracts. </i>
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  A contracting officer may not enter into a UCA for a foreign military sale unless—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  The UCA provides for agreement upon contractual terms, specifications, and price by the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the contractor submits a qualifying proposal; and </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  The contracting officer obtains approval from the head of the contracting activity to enter into a UCA in accordance with 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="i1378502" href="217.7404-1.dita#DFARS_217.7404-1">217.7404-1</xref>
            .  </p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  The head of the contracting activity may waive the requirements of paragraph (a)(1) of this section, if a waiver is necessary in order to support any of the following operations: </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  A contingency operation.</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  A humanitarian or peacekeeping operation.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b)  <i>Unilateral definitization by a contracting officer.  </i>Any UCA with a value greater than $50 million may not be unilaterally definitized until—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  The earlier of—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  The end of the 180-day period, beginning on the date on which the contractor submits a qualifying proposal to definitize the contractual terms, specifications, and price; or </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  The date on which the amount of funds expended under the contractual action is equal to more than 50 percent of the negotiated overall not-to-exceed price for the contractual action;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  The head of the contracting activity, without power of redelegation, approves the definitization in writing;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3)  The contracting officer provides a copy of the written approval to the contractor; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4)  A period of 30 calendar days has elapsed after the written approval is provided to the contractor.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
