<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_219.7102" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">219.7102</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p>The Program includes—</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) Mentor firms and protege firms that meet the criteria in <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" href="Appendix_I.dita#Appendix_I">I</xref>
            </ph>, section I-102<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">;</ph>
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) Mentor-protege agreements that establish a developmental assistance program for a protege firm<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">; </ph>
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List1" rev="Revised August 25, 2022">(c) A preliminary assessment of the protégé firm’s cybersecurity readiness. The DoD Office of Small Business Programs (OSBP), Office of the Under Secretary of Defense, Acquisition and Sustainment (OUSD(A&amp;S)), provides this preliminary assessment, which is a benefit of program participation; and </p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">d</ph>) Incentives that DoD may provide to mentor firms, <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">which include</ph>—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  Reimbursement for developmental assistance costs through—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  A separately priced contract line item on a DoD contract; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) A separate contract, upon written determination by the Director, (<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">O</ph>SBP), <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">of the cognizant military department or defense agency</ph> that unusual circumstances justify reimbursement using a separate contract; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  Credit toward applicable subcontracting goals, established under a subcontracting plan negotiated under FAR subpart 19.7 or under the DoD Comprehensive Subcontracting Test Program, for developmental assistance costs that are not reimbursed.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
