<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_219.800"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">219.800</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  By Partnership Agreement (PA) between the Small Business Administration (SBA) and the Department of Defense (DoD), the SBA has delegated to the Under Secretary of Defense <ph rev="Revised October 30, 2023">(Acquisition and Sustainment)</ph> its authority under paragraph 8(a)(1)(A) of the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 637(a)) to enter into 8(a) prime contracts, and its authority under 8(a)(1)(B) of the Small Business Act to award the performance of those contracts to eligible 8(a) Program participants.  However, the SBA remains the prime contractor on all 8(a) contracts, continues to determine eligibility of concerns for contract award, and retains appeal rights under FAR 19.810.  The SBA delegates only the authority to sign contracts on its behalf.  Consistent with the provisions of the PA, this authority is hereby redelegated to DoD contracting officers.  A copy of the PA, which includes the PA’s expiration date, is available at PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_219.800"
                  href="PGI_219.800.dita#DFARS_PGI_219.800"
                  xtrc="219.800">219.800</xref>
            .</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  Contracts awarded under the PA may be awarded directly to the 8(a) participant on either a sole source or competitive basis.  An SBA signature on the contract is not required.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  Notwithstanding the PA, the contracting officer may elect to award a contract pursuant to the provisions of FAR Subpart 19.8.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
