<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
   <concept id="DFARS_225.7013-2" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">225.7013-2</ph> Restrictions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contract award (10 U.S.C. 8679).</i> Do not award a contract to construct in a foreign shipyard—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2"> (1) A vessel for any of the armed forces; or </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2"> (2) A major component of the hull or superstructure of a vessel for any of the armed forces.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1"> (b) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Overhaul, repair, or maintenance (10 U.S.C. 8680).</i>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2"> (1) Do not overhaul, repair, or maintain, in a shipyard,outside the United States or Guam, a naval vessel (or any other vessel under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy) homeported in the United States or Guam.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) This restriction on overhaul, repair, or maintenance does not apply to—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (i) Voyage repairs; or</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) Repairs necessary to correct damage sustained due to hostile actions or interventions.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2"> (3) For a naval vessel classified as a littoral combat ship and operating on deployment—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (i) Corrective and preventive maintenance or repair, whether intermediate or depot level, and facilities maintenance may be performed if the work is performed by U.S. Government personnel or U.S. contractor personnel—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (A) In a foreign shipyard;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (B) At a facility outside of a foreign shipyard; or</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (C) At any other facility convenient to the vessel;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) Foreign workers may be used to perform corrective and preventive maintenance or repair, only if the Secretary of the Navy, without power of delegation, determines that travel by U.S. Government or contractor personnel to perform the maintenance or repair is not advisable for health or safety reasons; and</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (iii) Foreign contractors may perform facilities maintenance only as approved by the Secretary of <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised October 1, 2025">the</ph> Navy.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
