<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-225.403"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">225.403</ph> World Trade Organization Government Procurement Agreement and Free Trade Agreements.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  For acquisitions of supplies covered by the World Trade Organization Government Procurement Agreement, acquire only U.S.-made, qualifying country, or designated country end products unless—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  The contracting officer determines that offers of U.S.-made, qualifying country, or designated country end products from responsive, responsible offerors are either¾</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A)  Not received; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B)  Insufficient to fill the Government's requirements.  In this case, accept all responsive, responsible offers of U.S.-made, qualifying country, and eligible products before accepting any other offers; </p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  A national interest waiver under 19 U.S.C. 2512(b)(2) is granted on a case-by-case basis.  Except as delegated in paragraphs (c)(i)(A) and (B) of this section, submit any request for a national interest waiver to the Director of Defense Procurement and Acquisition Policy in accordance with department or agency procedures.  Include supporting rationale with the request.</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A)  The head of the contracting activity may approve a national interest waiver for a purchase by an overseas purchasing activity, if the waiver is supported by a written statement from the requiring activity that the products being acquired are critical for the support of U.S. forces stationed abroad.</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B)  The Commander or Director, Defense Energy Support Center, may approve national interest waivers for purchases of fuel for use by U.S. forces overseas; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(iii)  The acquisition is in support of operations in Afghanistan (see <ph xtrc="DFARxref" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     base="i1379454"
                     href="225.7704-1.dita#DFARS-225.7704-1">225.7704-1</xref>
            </ph>).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
