<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-225.371-3"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">225.371-3</ph> Government support.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Government support that may be authorized or required for contractor personnel performing in a designated operational area may include, but is not limited to, the types of support listed in PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_225.371-3"
                  href="PGI_225.371-3.dita#DFARS-PGI_PGI_225.371-3">225.371-3</xref>
            (a).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  The agency shall provide logistical or security support only when the appropriate agency official, in accordance with agency guidance, determines in coordination with the combatant commander that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Such Government support is available and is needed to ensure continuation of essential contractor services; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  The contractor cannot obtain adequate support from other sources at a reasonable cost.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  The contracting officer shall specify in the solicitation and contract—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Valid terms, approved by the combatant commander, that specify the responsible party, if a party other than the combatant commander is responsible for providing protection to the contractor personnel performing in the designated operational area;  and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Any other Government support to be provided, and whether this support will be provided on a reimbursable basis, citing the authority for the reimbursement.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(d)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Medical support of contractor personnel</i>.  The contracting officer shall provide direction to the contractor when the contractor is required to reimburse the Government for medical treatment or transportation of contractor personnel to a selected civilian facility in accordance with paragraph (c)(2)(ii) of the clause at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1382367"
                  href="252.225-7040.dita#DFARS-252.225-7040">252.225-7040</xref>
            . For additional information, see PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_225.371-3"
                  href="PGI_225.371-3.dita#DFARS-PGI_PGI_225.371-3">225.371-3</xref>
            (d).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(e)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Letter of authorization</i>.  Contractor personnel must have a Synchronized Predeployment and Operational Tracker (SPOT)–generated letter of authorization (LOA) signed by the contracting officer in order to process through a deployment center or to travel to, from, or within the designated operational area.  The LOA also will identify any additional authorizations, privileges, or Government support that the contractor personnel are entitled to under the contract.  For additional information on LOAs, see PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_225.371-3"
                  href="PGI_225.371-3.dita#DFARS-PGI_PGI_225.371-3">225.371-3</xref>
            (e).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
