<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_225.7705-2" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">225.7705-2</ph> Waiver of prohibition.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a) The prohibition in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" class="- topic/xref " base="i1379469" href="225.7705-1.dita#DFARS_225.7705-1">225.7705-1</xref>
             may be waived upon issuance of a determination, approved in accordance with paragraph (b) of this section, that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The program or project clearly contributes to United States national interests or strategic objectives; </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  The Government of Afghanistan has requested or expressed a need for the program or project;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  The program or project has been coordinated with the Government of Afghanistan, and with any other implementing agencies or international donors;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4)  Security conditions permit effective implementation and oversight of the program or project;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(5)  Safeguards to detect, deter, and mitigate corruption and waste, fraud, and abuse of funds are in place;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(6)  Adequate arrangements have been made for the sustainment of the program or project following its completion, including arrangements with respect to funding and technical capacity for sustainment; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(7)  Meaningful metrics have been established to measure the progress and effectiveness of the program or project in meeting its objectives.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  The following officials are authorized to approve the determination described in paragraph (a) of this section:</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  In the case of a program or project with an estimated lifecycle cost of less than $1 million, by the contracting officer.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  In the case of a program or project with an estimated lifecycle cost of $1 million or more, but less than $20 million, by the senior U.S. officer in the Combined Security Transition Command-Afghanistan. </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  In the case of a program or project with an estimated lifecycle cost of $20 million or more, but less than $40 million, by the Commander of United States Forces-Afghanistan.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4)  In the case of a program or project with an estimated lifecycle cost of $40 million or more, by the Secretary of Defense.  </p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  Congressional notification is required within 15 days of issuance of a determination to waive the prohibition for programs or projects valued at $40 million or more in accordance with paragraph (b)(4) of this section.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
