<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="DFARS_227.7102-1"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">227.7102-1</ph> Policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p id="KOUwvT" outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a) DoD shall acquire
only the technical data customarily provided to the public with
a commercial item or process, except technical data that—</p>
         <p id="kKitSI" outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) Are form, fit, or function
data;</p>
         <p id="YupnzB" outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) Are required for repair
or maintenance of commercial items or processes, or for the proper
installation, operating, or handling of a commercial item, either
as a stand alone unit or as a part of a military system, when such
data are not customarily provided to commercial users or the data
provided to commercial users is not sufficient for military purposes;
or</p>
         <p id="mVqAez" outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3) Describe the modifications
made at Government expense to a commercial item or process in order
to meet the requirements of a Government solicitation.</p>
         <p id="GQjShb" outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b) To encourage offerors
and contractors to offer or use commercial products to satisfy military
requirements, offerors and contractors shall not be required, except
for the technical data described in paragraph (a) of this subsection,
to—</p>
         <p id="RUkbpV" outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) Furnish technical information
related to commercial items or processes that is not customarily
provided to the public; or</p>
         <p id="JSHNjP" outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) Relinquish to, or otherwise
provide, the Government rights to use, modify, reproduce, release,
perform, display, or disclose technical data pertaining to commercial
items or processes except for a transfer of rights mutually agreed
upon.</p>
         <p id="jtTPYX" outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c) The Government's rights
in a vessel design, and in any useful article embodying a vessel
design, must be consistent with the Government's rights in technical
data pertaining to the design (10 U.S.C. <ph class="- topic/ph ">8687</ph>; 17 U.S.C. 1301(a)(3)).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
