<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_227.674" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">227.674</ph> Supply contracts between the Government and a foreign government or concern.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">In negotiating contract prices with a second source, including the redetermination of contract prices, or in determining the allowability of costs under a cost-reimbursement contract with a second source, the contracting officer:</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Shall obtain from the second source a detailed statement (see FAR 27.204-1(a)(2)) of royalties, license fees, and other compensation paid or to be paid to a primary source (or any of his subcontractors) for patent rights, rights in data, and other technical assistance provided to the second source, including identification and description of such patents, data, and technical assistance; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)	Shall not accept or allow charges which in effect are—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)	For royalties or amortization for patents or inventions in which the Government holds a royalty-free license; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  For data which the Government has a right to possess, use, and disclose to others; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  For any technical assistance provided to the second source for which the Government has paid under a contract between the Government and a primary source.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
