<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-227.7105-1"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">227.7105-1</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Existing works include motion pictures, television recordings, video recordings, and other audiovisual works in any medium; sound recordings in any medium; musical, dramatic, and literary works; pantomimes and choreographic works; pictorial, graphic, and sculptural works; and works of a similar nature.  Usually, these or similar works were not first created, developed, generated, originated, prepared, or produced under a Government contract.  Therefore, the Government must obtain a license in the work if it intends to reproduce the work, distribute copies of the work, prepare derivative works, or perform or display the work publicly.  When the Government is not responsible for the content of an existing work, it should require the copyright owner to indemnify the Government for liabilities that may arise out of the content, performance, use, or disclosure of such data.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  Follow the procedures at <ph xtrc="DFARxref" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     base="DFARS-227.7106"
                     href="227.7106.dita#DFARS-227.7106">227.7106</xref>
            </ph> for works which will be first created, developed, generated, originated, prepared, or produced under a Government contract and the Government needs to control distribution of the work or has a specific need to obtain indemnity for liabilities that may arise out of the creation, content, performance, use, or disclosure of the work or from libelous or other unlawful material contained in the work.  Follow the procedures at <ph xtrc="DFARxref" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     base="DFARS-227.7103"
                     href="227.7103.dita#DFARS-227.7103">227.7103</xref>
            </ph> when the Government does not need to control distribution of such works or obtain such indemnities.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
