<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-231.205-71"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">231.205-71</ph> Costs related to counterfeit electronic parts and suspect counterfeit electronic parts.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Scope</i>.  This section implements the requirements of section 818(c)(2), National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (Pub. L. 112-81), as modified by section 833, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (Pub. L. 112-239), and section 885 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (Pub. L. 114-92).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  The costs of counterfeit electronic parts and suspect counterfeit electronic parts and the costs of rework or corrective action that may be required to remedy the use or inclusion of such parts are unallowable, unless—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The contractor has an operational system to detect and avoid counterfeit electronic parts and suspect counterfeit electronic parts that has been reviewed and approved by DoD pursuant to <ph xtrc="DFARxref" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     base="DFARS-244.303"
                     href="244.303.dita#DFARS-244.303">244.303</xref>
            </ph>;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  The counterfeit electronic parts or suspect counterfeit electronic parts are Government-furnished property as defined in <ph xtrc="FARxref" class="- topic/ph ">FAR 45.101</ph> or were obtained by the contractor in accordance with the clause at <ph xtrc="DFARxref" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     base="i1384099"
                     href="252.246-7008.dita#DFARS-252.246-7008">252.246-7008</xref>
            </ph>, Sources of Electronic Parts; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  The contractor—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  Becomes aware of  the counterfeit electronic parts or suspect counterfeit electronic parts through inspection, testing, and authentication efforts of the contractor or its subcontractors; through a Government Industry Data Exchange Program (GIDEP) alert; or by other means; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  Provides timely (i.e., within 60 days after the contractor becomes aware) written notice to—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A)  The cognizant contracting officer(s); and</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B)  GIDEP (unless the contractor is a foreign corporation or partnership that does not have an office, place of business, or fiscal paying agent in the United States; or the counterfeit electronic part or suspect counterfeit electronic part is the subject of an on-going criminal investigation).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
