<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_232.7003" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">232.7003</ph> Procedures.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  DoD officials receiving payment requests in electronic form shall process the payment requests in electronic form.  The WAWF system provides the method to electronically process payment requests and receiving reports.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Documents necessary for payment, such as receiving reports, invoice approvals, contracts, contract modifications, and required certifications, shall also be processed in electronic form.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Scanned documents and other commonly used file formats are only acceptable for processing supporting documentation.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  If one of the exceptions to submission in electronic form at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" class="- topic/xref " base="DFARS-232.7002" href="232.7002.dita#DFARS_232.7002">232.7002</xref>
            (a) applies, the contracting officer shall—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Consult the payment office and the contract administration office regarding the alternative method to be used for submission of payment requests or receiving reports (e.g., facsimile or conventional mail); and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Provide procedures for invoicing in the contract administration data section of the contract or task or delivery order (e.g., section G, an addendum to FAR 52.212-4, or applicable clause) for submission of invoices by nonelectronic means.  If submission of invoices by nonelectronic means is temporary, the procedures should specify the time period for which they apply.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
