<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
   <concept id="DFARS_236.303-1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">236.303-1</ph> Phase One.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a)(4) In lieu of the limitations on the maximum number of offerors that may be selected to submit phase-two proposals at FAR 36.303-1(a)(4), for DoD—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (i) If the contract value exceeds $<ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised October 1, 2025">5.5</ph> million, the maximum number of offerors specified in the solicitation that are to be selected to submit phase-two proposals shall not exceed five, unless—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4">(A) The solicitation is issued for an indefinite-delivery indefinite-quantity contract for design-build construction; or</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4">(B) The head of the contracting activity, delegable to a level no lower than the senior contracting official within the contracting activity, approves the contracting officer’s decision with respect to an individual solicitation, that a maximum number greater than five is in the best interest of the Government and is consistent with the purposes and objectives of the two-phase selection procedures. The decision shall be documented in the contract file (U.S.C. 3241(d)).</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) If the contract value is at or below $<ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised October 1, 2025">5.5</ph> million, the maximum number of offerors specified in the solicitation that are to be selected to submit phase-two proposals is at the discretion of the contracting officer.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
