<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="DFARS_242.7203" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">242.7203</ph> Review procedures.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a)<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i "> Criteria for conducting reviews.</i>Conduct an MMAS review when—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(1) A contractor has $40 million of qualifying sales to the Government during the contractor's preceding fiscal year; and</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) The administrative contracting officer (ACO), with advice from the auditor, determines an MMAS review is needed based on a risk assessment of the contractor's past experience and current vulnerability.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(b) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Qualifying sales</i>. Qualifying sales are sales for which certified cost or pricing data were required under 10 U.S.C. 3702, as implemented in FAR 15.403, or that are contracts priced on other than a firm-fixed-price or fixed-price with economic price adjustment basis. Sales include prime contracts, subcontracts, and modifications to such contracts and subcontracts.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(c)<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i "> Disposition of findings</i>—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2"> (1) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Reporting of findings</i>. The auditor or functional specialist shall document findings and recommendations in a report to the contracting officer. If the auditor or functional specialist identifies any <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weakness</ph>, the report shall describe the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses or</ph> deficiencies in sufficient detail to allow the contracting officer to understand the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses or</ph> deficiencies.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Initial determination</i>. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (i) The contracting officer shall review findings and recommendations and, if there are no <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph>, shall promptly notify the contractor, in writing, that the contractor’s MMAS is acceptable and approved; or</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) If the contracting officer finds that there are one or more <xref href="http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/dfars/html/current/252242.htm#252.242-7004"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref "/> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> due to the contractor’s failure to meet one or more of the MMAS system criteria in the clause at <xref href="http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/dfars/html/current/252242.htm#252.242-7004"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.242-7004</xref>, the contracting officer shall—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (A) Promptly make an initial written determination on any <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025"/> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> and notify the contractor, in writing, providing a description of each <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weakness</ph> in sufficient detail to allow the contractor to understand the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weakness or </ph>deficiency;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4">(B) Request the contractor to respond, in writing, to the initial determination within 30 days; and</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (C) Promptly evaluate the contractor’s response to the initial determination in consultation with the auditor or functional specialist and make a final determination <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">(see PGI 242.7203(c)(2))</ph>.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(3) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Final determination</i>. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3">(i) The ACO shall make a final determination and notify the contractor that—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (A) The contractor’s MMAS is acceptable and approved, and no deficiencies remain<ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">;</ph> or</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (B) <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">Material weaknesses</ph> remain. The notice shall identify any remaining <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> and indicate the adequacy of any proposed or completed corrective action. The contracting officer shall—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5"> (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">1</i>) Request that the contractor, within 45 days of receipt of the final determination, either correct the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses</ph> or submit an acceptable corrective action plan showing milestones and actions to eliminate the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses</ph>;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5"> (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">2</i>) Disapprove the system in accordance with the clause at <xref href="http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/dfars/html/current/252242.htm#252.242-7004"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.242-7004</xref>; and</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">3</i>) Withhold payments in accordance with the clause at <xref href="252.242-7005.dita#DFARS_252.242-7005"
                  base="i1383876"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  xtrc="252.242-7005">252.242-7005</xref> , Contractor Business Systems, if the clause is included in the contract.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) Follow the procedures relating to monitoring a contractor’s corrective action and the correction of <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> in PGI <xref href="http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/pgi/pgi_htm/PGI242_72.htm#242.7203"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">242.7203</xref> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">(c)(3)</ph> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">.</ph> 
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1"> (d) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">System approval</i>. The contracting officer shall promptly approve a previously disapproved MMAS and notify the contractor when the contracting officer determines that there are no remaining <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph>.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(e) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting officer notifications</i>. The cognizant contracting officer shall promptly distribute copies of a determination to approve a system, disapprove a system and withhold payments, or approve a previously disapproved system and release withheld payments to the auditor; payment office; affected contracting officers at the buying activities; and cognizant contracting officers in contract administration activities.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
