<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="DFARS_245.105" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">245.105</ph> Contractors property management system compliance.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">. As used in this subpart</ph>—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p "
            rev="Revised January 17, 2025"
            outputclass="List1">“Acceptable property management system” means a property system that complies with the system criteria in paragraph (c) of the clause at 252.245-7003, Contractor Property Management Administration. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p "
            rev="Revised January 17, 2025"
            outputclass="List1"> “Property management system” means the contractor’s system or systems for managing and controlling Government property<ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">.</ph> 
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(b)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Policy</i>.  The cognizant contracting officer, in consultation with the property administrator, shall—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(1)  Determine the acceptability of the system and approve or disapprove the system; and</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) Pursue correction of any <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses or</ph> deficiencies.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(c)  In evaluating the acceptability of a contractor’s property management system, the contracting officer, in consultation with the property administrator, shall determine whether the contractor’s property management system complies with the system criteria for an acceptable property management system as prescribed in the clause at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1383966"
                  href="252.245-7003.dita#DFARS_252.245-7003"
                  xtrc="252.245-7003">252.245-7003</xref>
            , Contractor Property Management System Administration. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(d)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Disposition of findings</i>— </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2"> (1) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Reporting of findings</i>. The property administrator shall document findings and recommendations in a report to the contracting officer. If the property administrator identifies any <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph>, the report shall describe the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">underlying</ph> deficiencies in sufficient detail to allow the contracting officer to understand the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses or</ph> deficiencies.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Initial determination</i>. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (i) The contracting officer shall review findings and recommendations and, if there are no <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph>, shall promptly notify the contractor, in writing, that the contractor’s property management system is acceptable and approved; or</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) If the contracting officer finds that there are one or more <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/dfars/html/current/252245.htm#252.245-7003"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref "/> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> due to the contractor’s failure to meet one or more of the property management system criteria in the clause at <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/dfars/html/current/252245.htm#252.245-7003"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.245-7003</xref>, the contracting officer shall—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4">(A) Promptly make an initial written determination on any <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> and notify the contractor, in writing, providing a description of each <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weakness</ph> in sufficient detail to allow the contractor to understand the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weakness</ph> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">(see PGI 245.105(d)(2))</ph>;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4">(B)  Request the contractor to respond, in writing, to the initial determination within 30 days and;  </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4">(C)  Evaluate the contractor’s response to the initial determination, in consultation with the property administrator, and make a final determination. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(3) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Final determination</i>. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3">(i) The contracting officer shall make a final determination and notify the contractor, in writing, that— </p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (A) Promptly make an initial written determination on any <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> and notify the contractor, in writing, providing a description of each <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weakness</ph> in sufficient detail to allow the contractor to understand the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weakness</ph> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">(see PGI 245.105(d)(2))</ph>;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List4"> (B) <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">Material weaknesses</ph> remain. The notice shall identify any remaining <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph>and indicate the adequacy of any proposed or completed corrective action. The contracting officer shall—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">1</i>) Request that the contractor, within 45 days of receipt of the final determination, either correct the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses</ph> or submit an acceptable corrective action plan showing milestones and actions to eliminate the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">weaknesses</ph>;</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">2</i>) Disapprove the system in accordance with the clause at <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/dfars/html/current/252245.htm#252.245-7003"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.245-7003</xref>; and</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">3</i>) Withhold payments in accordance with the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1383876"
                  href="252.242-7005.dita#DFARS_252.242-7005"
                  xtrc="252.242-7005">252.242-7005</xref> , Contractor Business Systems, if the clause is included in the contract.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3"> (ii) Follow the procedures relating to monitoring a contractor’s corrective action and the correction of <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph> in <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/pgi/pgi_htm/PGI245_1.htm#245.105"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">PGI 245.105</xref> 
            <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">(d)(3)</ph>.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1"> (e) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">System approval</i>. The contracting officer shall promptly approve a previously disapproved property management system and notify the contractor when the contracting officer determines, in consultation with the property administrator, that there are no remaining <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised January 17, 2025">material weaknesses</ph>.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(f)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting officer notifications</i>.  The cognizant contracting officer shall promptly distribute copies of a determination to approve a system, disapprove a system and withhold payments, or approve a previously disapproved system and release withheld payments to the auditor; payment office; affected contracting officers at the buying activities; and cognizant contracting officers in contract administration activities. </p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
