<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_249.7003"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">249.7003</ph> Notification of anticipated contract terminations or reductions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a) Section 1372 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 (Pub. L. 103-160) and section 824 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997 (Pub. L. 104-201) are intended to help establish benefit eligibility under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (29 U.S.C. Chapter 32) for employees of DoD contractors and subcontractors adversely affected by termination or substantial reductions in major defense programs.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b) Departments and agencies are responsible for establishing procedures to—
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) Identify which contracts (if any) under major defense programs will be terminated or substantially reduced as a result of the funding levels provided in an appropriations act; and
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) Within 60 days of the enactment of such an act, provide notice of the anticipated termination of or substantial reduction in the funding of affected contracts—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i) Directly to the Secretary of Labor; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii) Through the contracting officer to each prime contractor.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c) When subcontracts have been issued, the prime contractor is responsible for—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) Providing notice of the termination or substantial reduction in funding to all first-tier subcontractors with a subcontract valued equal to or greater than $700,000; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) Requiring that each subcontractor—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i) Provide such notice to each of its subcontractors for subcontracts valued greater than $150,000; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii) Impose a similar notice and flowdown requirement in subcontracts valued greater than $150,000 at all tiers.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
