<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.225-7008" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">252.225-7008</ph> Restriction on Acquisition of Specialty Metals.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause">
         <p>As prescribed in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="i1379161" href="225.7003-5.dita#DFARS_225.7003-5">225.7003-5</xref>
            (a)(1), use the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">RESTRICTION ON ACQUISITION OF SPECIALTY METALS (MAR 2013)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a)  <i>Definitions</i>.  As used in this clause—</p>
         <p>“Alloy” means a metal consisting of a mixture of a basic metallic element and one or more metallic, or non-metallic, alloying elements.</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  For alloys named by a single metallic element (e.g., titanium alloy), it means that the alloy contains 50 percent or more of the named metal (by mass).</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  If two metals are specified in the name (e.g, nickel-iron alloy), those metals are the two predominant elements in the alloy, and together they constitute 50 percent or more of the alloy (by mass).</p>
         <p>“Produce” means—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  Atomization;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Sputtering; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Final consolidation of non-melt derived metal powders.</p>
         <p>“Specialty metal” means—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  Steel—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A)  With a maximum alloy content exceeding one or more of the following limits:  manganese, 1.65 percent; silicon, 0.60 percent; or copper, 0.60 percent; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B)  Containing more than 0.25 percent of any of the following elements:  aluminum, chromium, cobalt, molybdenum, nickel, niobium (columbium), titanium, tungsten, or vanadium;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  Metal alloys consisting of—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A)  Nickel or iron-nickel alloys that contain a total of alloying metals other than nickel and iron in excess of 10 percent; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B)  Cobalt alloys that contain a total of alloying metals other than cobalt and iron in excess of 10 percent; </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii)  Titanium and titanium alloys; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iv)  Zirconium and zirconium alloys.</p>
         <p>“Steel” means an iron alloy that includes between .02 and 2 percent carbon and may include other elements. </p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b)  Any specialty metal delivered under this contract shall be melted or produced in the United States or its outlying areas.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
