<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.209-7006" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">252.209-7006</ph> Limitations on Contractors Acting as Lead System Integrators.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="provision">
         <p>As prescribed in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="i1377837" href="209.570-4.dita#DFARS_209.570-4">209.570-4</xref>
            (a), use the following provision:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">LIMITATIONS ON CONTRACTORS ACTING AS LEAD SYSTEM INTEGRATORS (JAN 2008)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a)  <i>Definitions</i>.  “Lead system integrator,” “lead system integrator with system responsibility,” and “lead system integrator without system responsibility,” as used in this provision, have the meanings given in the clause of this solicitation entitled “Prohibited Financial Interests for Lead System Integrators” (DFARS 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="i1381168" href="252.209-7007.dita#DFARS_252.209-7007">252.209-7007</xref>
            ).  </p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b)  <i>General</i>.  Unless an exception is granted, no contractor performing lead system integrator functions in the acquisition of a major system by the Department of Defense may have any direct financial interest in the development or construction of any individual system or element of any system of systems.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c)  <i>Representations</i>.  </p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  The offeror represents that it does [ ] does not [ ] propose to perform this contract as a lead system integrator with system responsibility.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  The offeror represents that it does [ ] does not [ ] propose to perform this contract as a lead system integrator without system responsibility.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3)  If the offeror answered in the affirmative in paragraph (c)(1) or (2) of this provision, the offeror represents that it does [ ] does not [ ] have any direct financial interest as described in paragraph (b) of this provision with respect to the system(s), subsystem(s), system of systems, or services described in this solicitation.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d)  If the offeror answered in the affirmative in paragraph (c)(3) of this provision, the offeror should contact the Contracting Officer for guidance on the possibility of submitting a mitigation plan and/or requesting an exception.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(e)  If the offeror does have a direct financial interest, the offeror may be prohibited from receiving an award under this solicitation, unless the offeror submits to the Contracting Officer appropriate evidence that the offeror was selected by a subcontractor to serve as a lower-tier subcontractor through a process over which the offeror exercised no control.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(f)  This provision implements the requirements of 10 U.S.C. 2410p, as added by Section 807 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (Pub. L. 109-364).</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofprovision">(End of provision)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
