<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.225-7030" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">252.225-7030</ph> Restriction on Acquisition of Carbon, Alloy, and Armor Steel Plate.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause">
         <p>As prescribed in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="i1379291" href="225.7011-3.dita#DFARS_225.7011-3">225.7011-3</xref>
            , use the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">RESTRICTION ON ACQUISITION OF CARBON, ALLOY, AND ARMOR STEEL PLATE (DEC 2006)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a)  Carbon, alloy, and armor steel plate shall be melted and rolled in the United States or Canada if the carbon, alloy, or armor steel plate—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  Is in Federal Supply Class 9515 or is described by specifications of the American Society for Testing Materials or the American Iron and Steel Institute; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)(i)  Will be delivered to the Government for use in a Government-owned facility or a facility under the control of the Department of Defense; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  Will be purchased by the Contractor for use in a Government-owned facility or a facility under the control of the Department of Defense.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b)  This restriction—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  Applies to the acquisition of carbon, alloy, or armor steel plate as a finished steel mill product that may be used “as is” or may be used as an intermediate material for the fabrication of an end product; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  Does not apply to the acquisition of an end product (e.g., a machine tool), to be used in the facility, that contains carbon, alloy, or armor steel plate as a component.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
