<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.225-7060"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.225-7060</ph> Prohibition on Certain Procurements from the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p>As prescribed in 225.7022-5(b), use the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">PROHIBITION ON CERTAIN PROCUREMENTS FROM THE XINJIANG UYGHUR AUTONOMOUS REGION (DEC 2022)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (a) <i>Definitions</i>. As used in this clause—</p>
         <p> “Forced labor” means all work or service which is exacted from any person under the menace of any penalty for its nonperformance and for which the worker does not offer themselves voluntarily.</p>
         <p> “Person” means–</p>
         <p outputclass="List2"> (1) A natural person, corporation, company, business association, partnership, society, trust, or any other nongovernmental entity, organization, or group; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2"> (2) Any successor, subunit, parent entity, or subsidiary of, or any entity under common ownership or control with, any entity described in paragraph (1) of this definition.</p>
         <p> “XUAR” means the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (b) <i>Prohibition. </i>The Contractor shall not provide any products mined, produced, or manufactured wholly or in part by forced labor from XUAR or from an entity that has used labor from within or transferred from XUAR as part of any forced labor programs throughout the period of performance of the contract.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (c)  <i>Subcontracts</i>. The Contractor shall insert this clause, including this paragraph (c), without alteration other than to identify the appropriate parties, in subcontracts including subcontracts for commercial items and commercially available off-the-shelf items.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
