<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.234-7001"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.234-7001</ph> Notice of Earned Value Management System.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="provision" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-234.203"
                  href="234.203.dita#DFARS_234.203">234.203</xref>
            (1), use the following provision:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">NOTICE OF EARNED VALUE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (APR 2008)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  If the offeror submits a proposal in the amount of $50,000,000 or more—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The offeror shall provide documentation that the Cognizant Federal Agency (CFA) has determined that the proposed Earned Value Management System (EVMS) complies with the EVMS guidelines in the American National Standards Institute/Electronic Industries Alliance Standard 748, Earned Value Management Systems (ANSI/EIA-748) (current version at time of solicitation).  The Government reserves the right to perform reviews of the EVMS when deemed necessary to verify compliance.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  If the offeror proposes to use a system that has not been determined to be in compliance with the requirements of paragraph (a)(1) of this provision, the offeror shall submit a comprehensive plan for compliance with the guidelines in ANSI/EIA-748.</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  The plan shall—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A)  Describe the EVMS the offeror intends to use in performance of the contract, and how the proposed EVMS complies with the EVMS guidelines in ANSI/EIA-748;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B)  Distinguish between the offeror’s existing management system and modifications proposed to meet the EVMS guidelines;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(C)  Describe the management system and its application in terms of the EVMS guidelines;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(D)  Describe the proposed procedure for administration of the EVMS guidelines as applied to subcontractors; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(E)  Describe the process the offeror will use to determine subcontractor compliance with ANSI/EIA-748.</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  The offeror shall provide information and assistance as required by the Contracting Officer to support review of the plan.</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(iii)  The offeror’s EVMS plan must provide milestones that indicate when the offeror anticipates that the EVMS will be compliant with the guidelines in ANSI/EIA-748.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  If the offeror submits a proposal in an amount less than $50,000,000—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The offeror shall submit a written description of the management procedures it will use and maintain in the performance of any resultant contract to comply with the requirements of the Earned Value Management System clause of the contract.  The description shall include—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  A matrix that correlates each guideline in ANSI/EIA-748 (current version at time of solicitation) to the corresponding process in the offeror’s written management procedures; and </p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  The process the offeror will use to determine subcontractor compliance with ANSI/EIA-748.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  If the offeror proposes to use an EVMS that has been determined by the CFA to be in compliance with the EVMS guidelines in ANSI/EIA-748, the offeror may submit a copy of the documentation of such determination instead of the written description required by paragraph (b)(1) of this provision.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  The offeror shall identify the subcontractors (or the subcontracted effort if subcontractors have not been selected) to whom the EVMS requirements will apply.  The offeror and the Government shall agree to the subcontractors or the subcontracted effort selected for application of the EVMS requirements.  The offeror shall be responsible for ensuring that the selected subcontractors comply with the requirements of the Earned Value Management System clause of the contract.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofprovision" class="- topic/p ">(End of provision)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
