<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-252.204-7017"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.204-7017</ph> Prohibition on the Acquisition of Covered Defense Telecommunications Equipment or Services—Representation.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="provision" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-204.2105"
                  href="204.2105.dita#DFARS-204.2105">204.2105</xref>
            (b), use the following provision:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">PROHIBITION ON THE ACQUISITON OF COVERED DEFENSE TELECOMMUNICATIONS EQUIPMENT OR SERVICES—REPRESENTATION (DEC 2019)</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">The Offeror is not required to complete the representation in this provision if the Offeror has represented in the provision at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1381052"
                  href="252.204-7016.dita#DFARS-252.204-7016">252.204-7016</xref>
            , Covered Defense Telecommunications Equipment or Services—Representation, that it “does not provide covered defense telecommunications equipment or services as a part of its offered products or services to the Government in the performance of any contract, subcontract, or other contractual instrument.”</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)	<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>.  “Covered defense telecommunications equipment or services,” “covered mission,” “critical technology,” and “substantial or essential component,” as used in this provision, have the meanings given in the 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1381077"
                  href="252.204-7018.dita#DFARS-252.204-7018">252.204-7018</xref>
             clause, Prohibition on the Acquisition of Covered Defense Telecommunications Equipment or Services, of this solicitation.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Prohibition</i>.  Section 1656 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (Pub. L. 115-91) prohibits agencies from procuring or obtaining, or extending or renewing a contract to procure or obtain, any equipment, system, or service to carry out covered missions that uses covered defense telecommunications equipment or services as a substantial or essential component of any system, or as critical technology as part of any system.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Procedures</i>.  The Offeror shall review the list of excluded parties in the System for Award Management (SAM) at https://www.sam.gov for entities that are excluded when providing any equipment, system, or service to carry out covered missions that uses covered defense telecommunications equipment or services as a substantial or essential component of any system, or as critical technology as part of any system, unless a waiver is granted.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Representation</i>.  If in its annual representations and certifications in SAM the Offeror has represented in paragraph (c) of the provision at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1381052"
                  href="252.204-7016.dita#DFARS-252.204-7016">252.204-7016</xref>
            , Covered Defense Telecommunications Equipment or Services—Representation, that it “does” provide covered defense telecommunications equipment or services as a part of its offered products or services to the Government in the performance of any contract, subcontract, or other contractual instrument, then the Offeror shall complete the following additional representation:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">The Offeror represents that it [  ] will [  ] will not provide covered defense telecommunications equipment or services as a part of its offered products or services to DoD in the performance of any award resulting from this solicitation.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(e)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Disclosures</i>.  If the Offeror has represented in paragraph (d) of this provision that it “will provide covered defense telecommunications equipment or services,” the Offeror shall provide the following information as part of the offer:</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  A description of all covered defense telecommunications equipment and services offered (include brand or manufacturer; product, such as model number, original equipment manufacturer (OEM) number, manufacturer part number, or wholesaler number; and item description, as applicable).</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  An explanation of the proposed use of covered defense telecommunications equipment and services and any factors relevant to determining if such use would be permissible under the prohibition referenced in paragraph (b) of this provision.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  For services, the entity providing the covered defense telecommunications services (include entity name, unique entity identifier, and Commercial and Government Entity (CAGE) code, if known).</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4)  For equipment, the entity that produced or provided the covered defense telecommunications equipment (include entity name, unique entity identifier, CAGE code, and whether the entity was the OEM or a distributor, if known).	</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofprovision" class="- topic/p ">(End of provision)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
