<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="DFARS-252.232-7016"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.232-7016</ph>
          Notice of Progress Payments
or Performance-Based Payments.
      </title>
      <conbody outputclass="provision" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <xref href="232.1005-70.dita#DFARS-232.1005-70"
                  base="i1380179"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">232.1005-70</xref> (c), insert
the following provision:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">NOTICE OF PROGRESS PAYMENTS OR PERFORMANCE-BASED
PAYMENTS (APR 2020)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a) The need for customary progress payments
in accordance with subpart 32.5 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation
(FAR) or performance-based payments in accordance with FAR subpart
32.10 will not be considered as a handicap or adverse factor in
the award of the contract.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b) This solicitation includes a FAR and
Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement (DFARS) clause
for performance-based payments and a FAR clause for progress payments.
The resultant contract will include either performance-based payments
or progress payments, not both, except as may be authorized on separate
orders subject to FAR 32.1003(c).</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) The performance-based payments clauses
will be included in the contract if—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i) The Offeror has provided positive representation
in response to DFARS <xref href="252.232-7015.dita#DFARS-252.232-7015"
                  base="i1383322"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.232-7015</xref> ,
Performance-Based Payments—Representation;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii) The Offeror proposes a performance-based
payment arrangement in accordance with FAR 52.232-28, Invitation
to Propose Performance-Based Payments, including proposed events
and timing, event completion criteria, event values, and expected
expenditure profile; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(iii) The Offeror and the Government reach
agreement on all aspects of the arrangement.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) If performance-based payments clauses
are not included in the resultant contract, the progress payments
clause included in this solicitation will be included in any resultant
contract, modified or altered if necessary in accordance with FAR
52.232-16 and its Alternate I. Even though the progress payments
clause is included in the contract, the clause shall be inoperative
during any time the contractor’s accounting system and controls
are determined by the Government to be inadequate for segregation
and accumulation of contract costs.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofprovision" class="- topic/p ">(End of provision)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
