<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.225-7047"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.225-7047</ph> Exports by Approved Community Members in Performance of the Contract.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="i1379524"
                  href="225.7902-5.dita#DFARS_225.7902-5">225.7902-5</xref>
            (b), use the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">EXPORTS BY APPROVED COMMUNITY MEMBERS IN PERFORMANCE OF THE CONTRACT (JUNE 2013)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions.</i>  As used in this clause—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"Approved Community" means the U.S. Government, U.S. entities that are registered and eligible exporters, and certain government and industry facilities in Australia or the United Kingdom that are approved and listed by the U.S. Government.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Australia Community member” means an Australian government authority or nongovernmental entity or facility on the Australia Community list accessible at http://pmddtc.state.gov/treaties/index.html .</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"Defense articles" means articles, services, and related technical data, including software, in tangible or intangible form, listed on the United States Munitions List of the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR), as modified or amended. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Defense Trade Cooperation (DTC) Treaty" means— </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The Treaty Between the Government of the United States of America and the government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland concerning Defense Trade Cooperation, signed at Washington and London on June 21 and 26, 2007; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  The Treaty Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Australia Concerning Defense Trade Cooperation, signed at Sydney on September 5, 2007. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"Export" means the initial movement of defense articles from the United States Community to the United Kingdom Community and the Australia community.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"Implementing Arrangement" means – </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) The Implementing Arrangement Pursuant to the Treaty between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland Concerning Defense Trade Cooperation, signed on February 14, 2008; or</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  The Implementing Arrangement Pursuant to the Treaty between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Australia Concerning Defense Trade Cooperation, signed on March 14, 2008. </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Qualifying defense articles” means defense articles that are not exempt from the scope of the DTC Treaties as defined in 22 CFR 126.16(g) and 22 CFR 126.17(g).</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"Transfer" means the movement of previously exported defense articles within the Approved Community.  </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“United Kingdom Community member” means a United Kingdom government authority or nongovernmental entity or facility on the United Kingdom Community list accessible at http://pmddtc.state.gov.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"United States Community" means—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)	Departments and agencies of the U.S. Government, including their personnel, with, as appropriate, security accreditation and a need-to-know; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Nongovernmental U.S. entities registered with the Department of State and eligible to export defense articles under U.S. law and regulation, including their employees, with, as appropriate, security accreditation and a need-to-know.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">"U.S. DoD Treaty-eligible requirements" means any defense article acquired by the DoD for use in a combined military or counterterrorism operation, cooperative research, development, production or support program, or DoD end use, as described in Article 3 of the U.S.-U.K. DTC Treaty and sections 2 and 3 of the associated Implementing Arrangement; and Article 3 of the U.S.-Australia DTC Treaty and sections 2 and 3 of the associated Implementing Arrangement.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  All contract line items in this contract, except any identified in this paragraph, are intended to satisfy U.S. DoD Treaty-eligible requirements.  Specific defense articles that are not U.S. DoD Treaty-eligible will be identified as such in those contract line items that are otherwise U.S. DoD Treaty-eligible.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">CONTRACT LINE ITEMS NOT INTENDED TO SATISFY</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">U.S. DoD TREATY-ELIGIBLE REQUIREMENTS:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">______________________________________________________________</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">[Enter Contract Line Item Number(s) or enter "None"]</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  Subject to the other terms and conditions of this contract that affect the acceptability of foreign sources or foreign end products, components, parts, or materials, Approved Community members are permitted, but not required, to use the DTC Treaties for exports or transfers of qualifying defense articles in performance of the contract.  </p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(d)  Any conduct by the Contractor that falls outside the scope of the DTC Treaties, the Implementing Arrangements, and 22 CFR 126.16(g) and 22 CFR 126.17(g) is subject to all applicable ITAR requirements, including any criminal, civil, and administrative penalties or sanctions, as well as all other United States statutory and regulatory requirements outside of ITAR, including, but not limited to, regulations issued by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives found at 27 C.F.R. Parts 447, 478, and 479, which are unaffected by the DTC Treaties. </p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(e)  If the Contractor is an Approved Community member, the Contractor agrees that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  The Contractor shall comply with the requirements of the DTC Treaties, the Implementing Arrangements, the ITAR, and corresponding regulations of the U.S. Government and the government of Australia or the government of the United Kingdom, as applicable; and </p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Prior to the export or transfer of a qualifying defense article the Contractor—  </p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  Shall mark, identify, transmit, store, and handle any defense articles provided for the purpose of responding to such solicitations, as well as any defense articles provided with or developed pursuant to their responses to such solicitations, in accordance with the DTC Treaties, the Implementing Arrangements, and corresponding regulations of the United States Government and the government of Australia or the government of the United Kingdom, as applicable, including, but not limited to, the marking and classification requirements described in the applicable regulations;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  Shall comply with the re-transfer or re-export provisions of the DTC Treaties, the Implementing Arrangements, and corresponding regulations of the United States Government and the government of Australia or the government of the United Kingdom, as applicable, including, but not limited to, the re-transfer and re-export requirements described in the applicable regulations; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(iii)  Shall acknowledge that any conduct that falls outside or in violation of the DTC Treaties, Implementing Arrangements, and implementing regulations of the applicable government including, but not limited to, unauthorized re-transfer or re-export in violation of the procedures established in the applicable Implementing Arrangement and implementing regulations, remains subject to applicable licensing requirements of the government of Australia, the government of the United Kingdom, and the United States Government, including any criminal, civil, and administrative penalties or sanctions contained therein.   </p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(f)  The contractor shall include the substance of this clause, including this paragraph (f), in all subcontracts that may require exports or transfers of qualifying defense articles in connection with deliveries under the contract.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p "/>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
