<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="DFARS_SUBPART_APPENDIX_I_I_111"
            outputclass="3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">I-111</ph> Agreement terminations.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody " outputclass="List1">
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1"> (a) Mentors and/or protégés must send a copy of any termination notice to the <ph class="- topic/ph " rev="Revised March 26, 2024">Director, OSBP, OUSD(A&amp;S) or the</ph> Director, OSBP, of the cognizant military department or defense agency that approved the agreement, and the DCMA small business professional responsible for conducting the annual review pursuant to I–113.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(b) For reimbursable agreements, mentors must also send copies of any termination to the program manager and to the contracting officer.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(c) Termination of a mentor-protege agreement will not impair the obligations of the mentor firm to perform pursuant to its contractual obligations under Government contracts and subcontracts.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(d) Termination of all or part of the mentor-protege agreement will not impair the obligations of the protege firm to perform pursuant to its contractual obligations under any contract awarded to the protege firm by the mentor firm.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(e) Mentors and proteges will follow provisions of the mentor-protege agreement developed in compliance with I-107(l) through (n).</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(f) The Director, OSBP, OUSD(A&amp;S) or the Director, OSBP, of the military department or defense agency is authorized to terminate the mentor-protégé agreement for the convenience of the Government (to include national security grounds, funding limits, statutory requirements, or other considerations), as well as for cause upon written findings (e.g., either of the participants’ failure to perform or provide adequate assurance of performance; failure to comply with laws, regulations, and policies; conflicts of interest; or default under any provisions of a DoD contract or agreement).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
