<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="id2064F0S0O2H"
            outputclass="3"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">I-109</ph> Reimbursable agreements.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">The following provisions apply to all reimbursable mentor-protege agreements <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">including agreements that provide for both reimbursement and subcontracting credit</ph>:</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a) Assistance provided in the form of progress payments to a protege firm in excess of the customary progress payment rate for the firm will be reimbursed only if implemented in accordance with FAR 32.504(c).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b) Assistance provided in the form of advance payments will be reimbursed only if the payments have been provided to a protege firm under subcontract terms and conditions similar to those in the clause at FAR 52.232-12, Advance Payments. Reimbursement of any advance payments will be made pursuant to the inclusion of the clause at DFARS <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-252.232-7005"
                  href="252.232-7005.dita#DFARS_252.232-7005">252.232-7005</xref>, Reimbursement of Subcontractor Advance Payments—DoD Pilot Mentor-Protege Program, in appropriate contracts. In requesting reimbursement, the mentor firm agrees that the risk of any financial loss due to the failure or inability of a protege firm to repay any unliquidated advance payments will be the sole responsibility of the mentor firm.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c) The primary forms of developmental assistance authorized for reimbursement under the Program are identified in I-106(d). On a case-by-case basis,  Directors, <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">O</ph>SBP, <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">of the military departments or defense agencies</ph> at their discretion, may approve additional incidental expenses for reimbursement, provided these expenses do not exceed 10 percent of the total estimated cost of the agreement.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(d) The total amount reimbursed to a mentor firm for costs of assistance furnished to a protege firm in a fiscal year may not exceed $1<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022"> million</ph> unless the Director, <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">O</ph>SBP, of the military department or defense agency determines in writing that unusual circumstances justify reimbursement at a higher amount. Request for authority to reimburse in excess of $1 <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">million</ph> must detail the unusual circumstances and must be endorsed and submitted by the program manager to the Director, <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">O</ph>SBP<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">, of the military department or defense agency</ph>.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(e) DoD may not reimburse any fee to the mentor firm for services provided to the protege firm pursuant to I-106(d)(6) or for business development expenses incurred by the mentor firm under a contract awarded to the mentor firm while participating in a joint venture with the protege firm.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(f) Developmental assistance costs that are incurred pursuant to an approved reimbursable mentor-protege agreement, and have been charged to, but not reimbursed through, a separate contract, or through a separately priced contract line item added to a DoD contract, will not be otherwise reimbursed, as either a direct or indirect cost, under any other DoD contract, irrespective of whether the costs have been recognized for credit against applicable subcontracting goals.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
