<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="id2064F0S0OAZ" outputclass="3" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">I-105</ph> Mentor approval process.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) An entity seeking to participate as a mentor must apply to the <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">Mentor-Protégé Program Director, OSBP, OUSD(A&amp;S),</ph> to establish its initial eligibility as a mentor.<ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022"> </ph>
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The application must provide the following information:</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) A statement that the entity meets the requirements in I-102(a), specifying the criteria in I-102(a)(3) under which the entity is applying.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) A summary of the entity’s historical and recent activities and accomplishments under its small and disadvantaged business utilization program.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) The total dollar amount of DoD contracts and subcontracts that the entity received during the 2 preceding fiscal years. (Show prime contracts and subcontracts separately per year.)</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) The total dollar amount of all other Federal agency contracts and subcontracts that the entity received during the 2 preceding fiscal years. (Show prime contracts and subcontracts separately per year.)</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(5) The total dollar amount of subcontracts that the entity awarded under DoD contracts during the 2 preceding fiscal years.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(6) The total dollar amount of subcontracts that the entity awarded under all other Federal agency contracts during the 2 preceding fiscal years.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(7) The total dollar amount and percentage of subcontracts that the entity awarded to firms qualifying under I-102(b)(5)(i) through (vii) during the 2 preceding fiscal years. (Show DoD subcontract awards separately.) If the entity was required to submit a Summary Subcontract Report (SSR) in the Electronic Subcontracting Reporting System, the request must include copies of the final reports for the 2 preceding fiscal years.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(8) Information on the company’s ability to provide developmental assistance to its eligible proteges.</p>
         <p id="i1016745" outputclass="List1">(c) A template of the mentor application is available at: <ph rev="Revised August 25, 2022">
               <xref href="https://business.defense.gov/Programs/Mentor-Prot%C3%A9g%C3%A9-Program/MPP-Resources/" format="html" scope="external" />
            </ph>.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) Companies that apply for participation and are not approved will be provided the reasons and an opportunity to submit additional information for reconsideration.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
