<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_PGI_215.402" outputclass="3" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">PGI 215.402</ph> Pricing policy.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) Contracting officers must
purchase supplies and services from responsible sources at fair
and reasonable prices. The Truth in Negotiations Act (TINA) (10
U.S.C. 2306a and 41 U.S.C. chapter 35) requires offerors to submit
certified cost or pricing data if a procurement exceeds the TINA
threshold and none of the exceptions to certified cost or pricing
data requirements applies. Under TINA, the contracting officer obtains
accurate, complete, and current data from offerors to establish
a fair and reasonable price (see FAR 15.403).
TINA also allows for a price adjustment remedy if it is later found
that a contractor did not provide accurate, complete, and current
data.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) When certified cost or pricing data
are not required, and the contracting officer does not have sufficient
data to determine price reasonableness, FAR
15.402(a)(2) requires the offeror to provide whatever data
the contracting officer needs in order to determine fair and reasonable
prices.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) Obtaining sufficient data from the
offeror is particularly critical in situations where an item is
determined to be a commercial item in accordance with FAR 2.101and the contract is being awarded
on a sole source basis. This includes commercial sales data of items
sold in similar quantities and, if such data is insufficient, cost
data to support the proposed price.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) See PGI 
               <xref href="PGI_215.404-1.dita#DFARS_PGI_PGI_215.404-1" base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_215.404-1" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" xtrc="215.404-1">215.404-1</xref>
             and
the Department of Defense Guidebook for Acquiring Commercial Items, 
               <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/cpic/cp/docs/Guidebook_Part_B_Commercial_Item_Pricing_20180126.pdf" format="pdf" scope="external">Part B: Pricing Commercial
Items</xref>
            , for more detailed procedures and guidance on
obtaining data needed to determine fair and reasonable prices.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
