<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_PGI_215.403-1"
            outputclass="4"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">PGI 215.403-1</ph> Prohibition onobtaining certified cost or pricing data (10 U.S.C. chapter 271 and 41U.S.C. chapter 35).</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Exceptions to certified
cost or pricing data requirements</i>. Even if an exception to certified
cost or pricing data applies, the contracting officer is still required
to determine price reasonableness. In order to make this determination,
the contracting officer may require data other than certified cost
or pricing data, including data related to prices and cost data
that would otherwise be defined as certified cost or pricing data
if certified.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)(3) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Commercial <ph rev="Revised January 31, 2023">products or commercial services</ph>
            </i>. See the Department of Defense Guidebook for Acquiring Commercial Items, <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/cpic/cp/docs/Guidebook_Part_B_Commercial_Item_Pricing_20180126.pdf"
                  format="pdf"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">Part B: Pricing Commercial Items</xref> , for detailed guidance about techniques and approaches to pricing commercial products and <ph rev="Revised January 31, 2023">commercial </ph>services.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Waivers</i>.</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Exceptional case TINA waiver</i>.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">1</i>) In determining that an exceptional case TINA
waiver is appropriate, the head of the contracting activity (HCA) must exercise care to ensure that the
supplies or services could not be obtained without the waiver and that the
determination is clearly documented. <xref href="http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/policy/policyvault/2007-0195-DPAP.pdf"
                  format="pdf"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">See DPAP March 23, 2007,
policy memorandum</xref> . The intent is not to relieve entities that normally
perform Government contracts subject to TINA from an obligation to certify that
cost or pricing data are accurate, complete, and current. Instead, waivers must
be used judiciously, in situations where the Government could not otherwise
obtain a needed item without a waiver. A prime example would be when a
particular company offers an item that is essential to DoD’s mission but is not
available from other sources, and the company refuses to submit certified cost
or pricing data. In such cases, a waiver may be appropriate. However, the
procuring agency should, in conjunction with the waiver, develop a strategy for
procuring the item in the future that will not require such a waiver (e.g.,
develop a second source, develop an alternative product that satisfies the
department’s needs, or have DoD produce the item).</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">2</i>) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Senior procurement executive
coordination</i>. An exceptional case TINA waiver that exceeds $100
million shall be coordinated with the senior procurement executive
prior to granting the waiver.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">3</i>) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Waiver for part
of a proposal</i>. The requirement for submission of certified cost or pricing
data may be waived for part of an offeror’s proposed price when it is possible
to clearly identify that part of the offeror’s cost proposal to which the waiver
applies as separate and distinct from the balance of the proposal. In granting a
partial waiver, in addition to complying with the requirements in DFARS <xref href="215.403-1.dita#DFARS_215.403-1"
                  base="DFARS-215.403-1"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">215.403-1</xref>(c)(4), the
(HCA) must address why it is in the
Government’s best interests to grant a partial waiver, given that the offeror
has no objection to certifying to the balance of its cost proposal.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">4</i>) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Waivers for unpriced supplies
or services</i>. Because there is no price, unpriced supplies or
services cannot be subject to cost or pricing data certification
requirements. The Government cannot agree in advance to waive certification
requirements for unpriced supplies or services, and may only consider
a waiver at such time as an offeror proposes a price that would
otherwise be subject to certification requirements.</p>
         <p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B) The annual report of waiver of TINA
requirements shall include the following:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List5">Title: Waiver of TINA
Requirements</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(1) Contract number, including modification
number, if applicable, and program name.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(2) Contractor name.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(3) Contracting activity.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(4) Total dollar amount waived.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(5) Brief description of why the item(s) could not be
obtained without a waiver. <xref href="https://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/policy/policyvault/2007-0195-DPAP.pdf"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external">See DPAP March 23, 2007, policy
memorandum</xref>.
         </p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(6) Brief description of the specific steps
taken to ensure price reasonableness.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(7) Brief description of the demonstrated
benefits of granting the waiver.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
