<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
    <concept id="DFARS_PGI_215.406-2" rev="Revised October 30, 2023">
        <title rev="Revised October 30, 2023">
         <ph props="autonumber">PGI 215.406-2</ph> Certificate of current cost or pricing data.</title>
        <conbody>
            <p outputclass="List3">(c)(i) Prior to the start of negotiations, contracting officers should notify offerors and contractors that—</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List4"> (A) A Certificate of Current Cost or Pricing Data, as prescribed by FAR 15.406-2, shall be submitted as soon as practicable after agreement on price (preferably within 5 days after price agreement), but before contract award or execution of a modification (except for unpriced actions such as letter contracts).</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List4"> (B) A Certificate of Current Cost or Pricing Data that deviates from the language specified in FAR 15.406-2, or has been amended to include certification of data submitted after the date of price agreement, will not be accepted.</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List3"> (ii) If any data is submitted after the date of price agreement, contracting officers shall—</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List4"> (A) Notify offerors in writing that such data will not be reviewed until after contract award and will be dispositioned in accordance with FAR 15.407-1 and FAR clause 52.215-10 or 52.215-11, as applicable; or</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List4"> (B) Consider the previous price agreement null and void, and prior to award—</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List6"> (<i>1</i>) Reopen negotiations to assess the impact of the data submitted after the date of price agreement (“sweep data”);</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List6"> (<i>2</i>) Reestablish price agreement based on cost or pricing data that is accurate, complete, and current as of the date of the revised agreement on price; and</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List6"> (<i>3</i>) Request a new Certificate of Current Cost or Pricing Data, as prescribed by FAR 15.406-2, to include the sweep data and any new or revised data submitted after the previous certification.</p>
            
            <p outputclass="List3"> (iii) If a contractor persistently submits untimely “sweep” data or fails to timely submit cost or pricing data or the certification that the data are accurate, complete, and current as of the data of price agreement, the contracting officer should refer the matter to the Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA) via the Administrative Contracting Officer, Divisional Administrative Contracting Officer, or Corporate Administrative Contracting Officer, as appropriate, for consideration in DCAA’s review of the adequacy of the contractor’s estimating system.</p>
        </conbody>
    </concept>
</dita>
