<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_PGI_219.201"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">PGI 219.201</ph> General policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)(10)(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">1</i>)
            Agencies are not precluded from requiring that actions over the micro-purchase threshold, but under the
            simplified acquisition threshold, that are totally set aside for small business be
            reviewed by the small business specialist. One example of when an agency may choose to
            require this review is when the agency determines that such a review is necessary to
            assist contracting officers in identifying opportunities for other small business
            set-aside programs (e.g., HUBZone, service-disabled veteran-owned, small disadvantaged
            business, women-owned small business) in order to meet small business goals.</p>
         <p outputclass="List6" class="- topic/p ">(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">2</i>) Modifications that increase the scope of the contract, or the order under a Federal Supply Schedule contract, should be reviewed by the small business specialist. At a minimum, these actions might impact the small business subcontracting plan. However, funding modifications or modifications that do not increase the scope of the contract generally should not be reviewed, because the value that a small business specialist review would add in these instances would be minimal compared to the resources that would be expended.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(d) Small business specialists are appointed and perform functions in accordance with DoD Instruction (DoDI) 4205.01, DoD Small Business Programs. In the DoDI, small business specialists are called “small business professionals.”</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
