<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_232.671"
            outputclass="3"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">PGI 232.671</ph> Bankruptcy reporting.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) For those debts covered by this subpart, the department or agency that awarded the contract shall furnish the Department of Justice any claims in bankruptcy, insolvency, or in proceedings for reorganization or arrangement. Furnish claims that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i) Have been transferred to a contract financing office;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii) Are on the way to a contract financing office at the inception of bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(iii) Are pending and not forwarded to a contract financing office at the inception of bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(iv) Are the result of bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) The contract financing office or other office designated within a department or agency will furnish proof of claims to the Department of Justice.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3) The office of origin of a debt will provide, as soon as possible, information on a bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, or rearrangement to the office designated within a department/agency to receive this information.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(4) The information and proof of claim requirements in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this section do not apply to debts of less than $600.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
