<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_PGI_246.370" outputclass="3" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">PGI 246.370</ph> Notification of potential safety issues.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1)  The objective of this requirement is to ensure that the Government receives timely notification of potential safety defects so that—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  Systems and equipment likely affected by the situation can be identified; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  An appropriate engineering investigation and follow-on actions can be taken to establish and mitigate risk.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2)  The notification is intended to be neither an admission of nor a release from liability.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3)  Upon notification of a potential safety nonconformance or deficiency—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i)  The procuring contracting officer must—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A)  Advise the affected program office(s) or integrated materiel manager(s); and </p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B)  Request a point of contact from the affected program office(s) or materiel management organization to assess the impact of the situation, address technical concerns, and provide recommendations;</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii)  The administrative contracting officer must—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A)  Confirm that potentially affected program offices, integrated materiel managers, and other contract management offices that may be recipients of the suspect items are aware of the situation; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B)  Identify a point of contact to provide support and technical assistance to the investigative team; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii)  For replenishment parts, the integrated materiel manager must—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A)  Identify any potentially affected programs or equipment; and </p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B)  Request engineering assistance from affected engineering support activities, as prescribed by—</p>
         <p outputclass="List6">
            <i>(1)</i>  DLAI 3200.1/PAM 715.13/NAVSUPINST 4120.30A/AFI 21-408/MCO 4000.18, Engineering Support Instruction for Items Supplied by Defense Logistics Agency; </p>
         <p outputclass="List6">
            <i>(2)</i>  SECNAVINST 4140.2/AFI 20-106/DA PAM 95-9/DLAI 3200.4/DCMA INST CSI (AV), Management of Aviation Critical Safety Items; </p>
         <p outputclass="List6">
            <i>(3)</i>  DA PAM 738-751, Functional Users Manual for the Army Maintenance Management System—Aviation (TAMMS-A); </p>
         <p outputclass="List6">
            <i>(4)</i>  AMCOM REG 702-7, Flight Safety Parts/New Source Testing Program Management; or </p>
         <p outputclass="List6">
            <i>(5)</i>  Internal agency procedures. </p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
