<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_205.205"
            outputclass="3"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            rev="Revised October 30, 2023">
      <title class="- topic/title " rev="Revised October 30, 2023"> 
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">PGI 205.205</ph> Special situations.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (h) Notice regarding timely definitization of equitable adjustments for change orders under construction contracts. To obtain definitization data for requests for equitable adjustment to include in solicitations for construction contracts, access the PALT/Protest/REA Tracker module in the Procurement Integrated Enterprise Environment (PIEE) website at https://piee.eb.mil. Search the PALT/Protest/REA Tracker for the applicable military department or defense agency data and— </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) If data exists, download the table and include it as an attachment to the solicitation notice in the Governmentwide point of entry (GPE); or </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) If no data exists, then include the following statement in the Description section of the solicitation notice: “No data is available regarding the timely definitization of equitable adjustments for change orders under construction contracts.” (See PGI 236.211(b)(2) for reporting data on definitization of equitable adjustments.) </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Include a description of military department or defense agency policies or procedures, in addition to that outlined in FAR 43.204, that apply to definitization of equitable adjustments for change orders under construction contracts. This description may be provided in a notice by including an address of an agency-specific, publicly available website containing this information. </p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iv) If the military department or defense agency does not have agency-specific procedures, include the following statement: “There are no agency-specific policies or procedures that apply to the definitization of equitable adjustments for change orders under construction contracts.” </p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
