<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_PGI_PGI_208.406-1" outputclass="4" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">PGI 208.406-1</ph> Order placement.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) When ordering from schedules, ordering offices—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) May use DD Form 1155, Order for Supplies or Services, to place orders for—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A) Commercial items at or below the simplified acquisition threshold; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B) Other than commercial items at any dollar value (see PGI 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="DFARS-PGI_PGI_213.307" href="PGI_213.307.dita#DFARS_PGI_PGI_213.307" xtrc="213.307">213.307</xref>
            );</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Shall use SF 1449, Solicitation/Contract/Order for Commercial Items, to place orders for commercial items exceeding the simplified acquisition threshold (see FAR 12.204); and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii) May use SF 1449 to place orders for other than commercial items at any dollar value.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) Schedule orders may be placed orally if—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) The contractor agrees to furnish a delivery ticket for each shipment under the order (in the number of copies required by the ordering office). The ticket must include the—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A) Contract number;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B) Order number under the contract;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(C) Date of order;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(D) Name and title of person placing the order;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(E) Itemized listing of supplies or services furnished; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(F) Date of delivery or shipment; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Invoicing procedures are agreed upon. Optional methods of submitting invoices for payment are permitted, such as—</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(A) An individual invoice with a receipted copy of the delivery ticket;</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(B) A summarized monthly invoice covering all oral orders made during the month, with receipted copies of the delivery tickets (this option is preferred if there are many oral orders); or</p>
         <p outputclass="List4">(C) A contracting officer statement that the Government has received the supplies.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) For purchases where cash payment is an advantage, the use of imprest funds in accordance with DFARS <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly" base="DFARS-213.305" href="213.305.dita#DFARS_213.305" xtrc="213.305">213.305</xref> is authorized when—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) The order does not exceed the threshold at FAR 13.305-3(a); and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) The contractor agrees to the procedure.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) If permitted under the schedule contract, use of the Governmentwide commercial purchase card—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) Is mandatory for placement of orders valued at or below the micro-purchase threshold; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Is optional for placement of orders valued above the micro-purchase threshold.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
