<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS-PGI_PGI_217.7405"
            outputclass="3"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">PGI 217.7405</ph> Plans and reports.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) By October 31 and April 30 of each year, departments and agencies shall submit an updated Consolidated UCA Management Plan, and a Consolidated UCA Management Report, identifying each UCA with a value exceeding $5 million. In addition, departments and agencies shall submit a copy of the record of weighted guidelines for each definitized UCA with a value of $100 million or more. If there is no record of weighted guidelines (e.g., not required for a cost plus award fee contract per DFARS 215.404-74), then departments and agencies shall submit alternative documentation that addresses appropriate recognition of the contractor’s reduced cost risk during the undefinitized performance period. Submit the required information to—</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">Deputy Director, Defense Procurement and Acquisition Policy </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">(Contract Policy and International Contracting)</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">3060 Defense Pentagon</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">Washington, DC 20301-3060.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) The Consolidated UCA Management Plan and the Consolidated UCA Management Report shall be prepared using the following formats:</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Consolidated UCA Management Plan:</i>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">Title: Consolidated Undefinitized Contract Action (UCA) Management Plan Period Covered:</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">1. Applicable military department, defense agency, or DoD component. a. Headquarters point of contact. b. Contact information.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">2. Description of actions planned and taken to ensure: a. Appropriate use of UCAs. b. Timely definitization of UCAs. c. Minimized obligation amounts at the time of UCA award, consistent with the contractor’s requirements for the undefinitized period. d. In determining profit/fee, appropriate recognition of the contractor’s reduced cost risk during the undefinitized performance period. e. Documentation of the risk assessment in the contract file.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">3. Milestones for completion of planned events.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">4. Other.</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Consolidated UCA Management Report:</i>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">The required format for the Consolidated UCA Management Report is available at this website: http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/pgi/docs/uca_management_report_2015(updated22Mar16).xlsx.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3) A list of Frequently Asked Questions about UCA reporting requirements is available at this website: http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars/pgi/docs/faq_201603.docx.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
