<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
   <concept id="DFARS_236.272"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">236.272</ph> Prequalification of sources.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Prequalification procedures may be used when necessary to ensure timely and efficient performance of critical construction projects.  Prequalification—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Results in a list of sources determined to be qualified to perform a specific construction contract; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Limits offerors to those with proven competence to perform in the required manner.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  The head of the contracting activity must—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Authorize the use of prequalification by determining, in writing, that a construction project is of an urgency or complexity that requires prequalification; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Approve the prequalification procedures.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  For small businesses, the prequalification procedures must require the qualifying authority to—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1)  Request a preliminary recommendation from the appropriate Small Business Administration regional office, if the qualifying authority believes a small business is not responsible;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2)  Permit the small business to submit a bid or proposal if the preliminary recommendation is that the small business is responsible; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3)  Follow the procedures in FAR 19.6, if the small business is in line for award and is found nonresponsible.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
