<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.225-7060"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.225-7060</ph> Prohibition on Certain Procurements from the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p>As prescribed in 225.7022-5(b), use the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">PROHIBITION ON CERTAIN PROCUREMENTS FROM THE XINJIANG UYGHUR AUTONOMOUS REGION (JUN 2023)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (a) <i>Definitions</i>. As used in this clause—</p>
         <p> “Forced labor” means any work or service that is exacted from any person under the menace of any penalty for its nonperformance and that the worker does not offer to perform 
            (10 U.S.C. 2496).</p>
         <p> “XUAR” means the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China (10 U.S.C. 2496).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (b) <i>Prohibition. </i>
            In accordance with 10 U.S.C. 4661, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available for DoD may be used to knowingly procure any products mined, produced, or manufactured wholly or in part by forced labor from XUAR or from an entity that has used labor from within or transferred from XUAR.The Contractor shall make a good faith effort to determine that forced labor from XUAR will not be used in the performance of this contract (section 855, Pub. L. 117-263).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) <i>Subcontracts</i>. The Contractor shall insert this clause, including this paragraph (c), without alteration other than to identify the appropriate parties, in subcontracts including subcontracts for commercial products, commercial services, and commercially available off-the-shelf items.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
