<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_227.7103-6"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">227.7103-6</ph> Contract clauses.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a) Use the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-252.227-7013"
                  href="252.227-7013.dita#DFARS_252.227-7013">252.227-7013</xref>, Rights in Technical Data-Noncommercial Other Than Commercial Products and Commercial Services, in solicitations and contracts, including solicitations and contracts using FAR part 12 procedures for the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services, when the successful offeror(s) will be required to deliver to the Government technical data pertaining to other than commercial products or commercial services, or pertaining to commercial products or commercial services for which the Government will have paid for any portion of the development costs (in which case the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-252.227-7013"
                  href="252.227-7013.dita#DFARS_252.227-7013">252.227-7013</xref> will govern the technical data pertaining to any portion of a commercial product or commercial service that was developed in any part at Government expense, and the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-252.227-7015"
                  href="252.227-7015.dita#DFARS_252.227-7015">252.227-7015</xref> will govern the technical data pertaining to any portion of a commercial product or commercial service that was developed exclusively at private expense). Do not use the clause when the only deliverable items are computer software or computer software documentation (see 227.72), commercial products or commercial services developed exclusively at private expense (see <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="DFARS-227.7102-4"
                  href="227.7102-4.dita#DFARS_227.7102-4">227.7102-4</xref>), existing works (see <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="227.7105.dita#DFARS_227.7105"
                  base="DFARS-227.7105"
                  class="- topic/xref ">227.7105</xref> ), special works (see <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="227.7106.dita#DFARS_227.7106"
                  base="DFARS-227.7106"
                  class="- topic/xref ">227.7106</xref> ), or when contracting under the Small Business Innovation Research Program (see <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="227.7104.dita#DFARS_227.7104"
                  base="DFARS-227.7104"
                  class="- topic/xref ">227.7104</xref> ). Except as provided in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="227.7107-2.dita#DFARS_227.7107-2"
                  base="i1379774"
                  class="- topic/xref ">227.7107-2</xref> , do not use the clause in architect-engineer and construction contracts.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)(1) Use the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7013.dita#DFARS_252.227-7013"
                  base="i1382636"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7013</xref> with its Alternate I in research solicitations and contracts, including research solicitations and contracts using FAR part 12 procedures for the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services, when the contracting officer determines, in consultation with counsel, that public dissemination by the contractor would be—</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i) In the interest of the Government; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii) Facilitated by the Government relinquishing its right to publish the work for sale, or to have others publish the work for sale on behalf of the Government.</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) Use the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7013.dita#DFARS_252.227-7013"
                  base="i1382636"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7013</xref> with its Alternate II in solicitations and contracts, including solicitations and contracts using FAR part 12 procedures for the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services, that are for the development or delivery of a vessel design or any useful article embodying a vessel design.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c) Use the clause at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7025.dita#DFARS_252.227-7025"
                  base="i1382915"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7025</xref>
            , Limitations on the Use or Disclosure of Government-Furnished Information Marked with Restrictive Legends, in solicitations and contracts when it is anticipated that the Government will provide the contractor (other than a litigation support contractor covered by 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.204-7014.dita#DFARS_252.204-7014"
                  base="i1381025"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.204-7014</xref>
            ), for performance of its contract, technical data marked with another contractor's restrictive legend(s).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(d) Use the provision at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7028.dita#DFARS_252.227-7028"
                  base="i1382940"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7028</xref>
            , Technical Data or Computer Software Previously Delivered to the Government, in solicitations when the resulting contract will require the contractor to deliver technical data. The provision requires offerors to identify any technical data specified in the solicitation as deliverable data items that are the same or substantially the same as data items the offeror has delivered or is obligated to deliver, either as a contractor or subcontractor, under any other federal agency contract.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(e) Use the following clauses in solicitations and contracts that include the clause at 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7013.dita#DFARS_252.227-7013"
                  base="i1382636"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7013</xref>
            :</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(1) 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7016.dita#DFARS_252.227-7016"
                  base="i1382771"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7016</xref>
            , Rights in Bid or Proposal Information;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(2) 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7030.dita#DFARS_252.227-7030"
                  base="i1382950"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7030</xref>
            , Technical Data–Withholding of Payment; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2" class="- topic/p ">(3) 
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  href="252.227-7037.dita#DFARS_252.227-7037"
                  base="i1382985"
                  class="- topic/xref ">252.227-7037</xref>
            , Validation of Restrictive Markings on Technical Data (paragraph (e) of the clause contains information that must be included in a challenge).</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
