<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
   <concept id="DFARS_252.237-7026"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">252.237-7026</ph> Postaward Transparency Requirements for Firms that Support Department of Defense Audits.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="provision" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p>As prescribed in <xref href="237.270.dita#DFARS_237.270" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">237.270</xref>(e)(4), use the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps"> POSTAWARD TRANSPARENCY REQUIREMENTS FOR FIRMS THAT SUPPORT DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE AUDITS (OCT 2022)</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (a) Prior to each contract action under this contract (including renewal or modification), the Contractor shall disclose the details of any disciplinary proceedings, with respect to the firm and/or its principals or employees, before an entity with the authority to enforce compliance with rules or laws applying to audit services or audit remediation services offered by the Contractor, and whether there has been any change with regard to previously reported proceedings since the last contract action.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (b) The disclosure shall, at a minimum, include—</p>
         <p outputclass="List2"> (1) The entity hearing the case;</p>
         <p outputclass="List2"> (2) The case or file number; and</p>
         <p outputclass="List2"> (3) A brief description of the allegation or conduct at issue and, if fully adjudicated or settled, a brief description of the outcome.</p>
         <p outputclass="List1"> (c) The Government will safeguard and treat as confidential all statements provided pursuant to this clause where the statement has been marked “confidential” or “proprietary” by the Contractor. Statements so marked will not be released by the Government to the public pursuant to a request under the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. 552, without prior notification to the Contractor and opportunity for the Contractor to claim an exemption from release. The Government will treat any statement provided pursuant to this clause as confidential to the extent required by any other applicable law.</p>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
